foodnetwork.co.uk 2014-12-18

# Privacy And Cookies Policy : Food Network UK

WHEN YOU ACCESS OUR WEBSITE, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, OR TO ANY CHANGES WE MAY SUBSEQUENTLY MAKE, IMMEDIATELY STOP ACCESSING OUR WEBSITE. 

Welcome to foodnetwork.co.uk. foodnetwork.co.uk (“Website”) is an interactive online service operated by Scripps Networks International (UK) Limited (“us”, “we”, or “our”). Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. 

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 ("Act") the data controller is Scripps Networks International (UK) Limited with a registered address of One Fleet Place, London, EC4M 7WS.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting personally identifiable information you may provide us through our Website. We have adopted this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) to explain what information may be collected on our Website, how we use this information, and under what circumstances we may disclose the information to third parties. This Privacy Policy applies only to information we collect through our Website and does not apply to our collection of information from other sources. 

This Privacy Policy, together with the Terms of Use posted on our Website, sets forth the general rules and policies governing your use of our Website. Depending on your activities when visiting our Website, you may be required to agree to additional terms and conditions. 

We keep this Privacy Policy posted on our Website and you should review it frequently, as it may change from time to time.. Any changes we make to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this Website, and where appropriate, notified to you be email.

#### A. INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

Our Website typically collects two kinds of information about you: (a) information that you provide that personally identifies you; and (b) information that does not personally identify you, that we automatically collect when you visit our Website or that you provide us. 

  * (1) Personally Identifiable Information: 
  * Personally identifiable information includes any information that may be used to identify or contact you, such as your name, mail address, phone number, etc. We do not automatically collect your personally identifiable information when you visit our Website. In certain circumstances, we may request, allow or otherwise provide you an opportunity to submit your personally identifiable information in connection with a feature, program, promotion or some other aspect of our Website. For instance, you may: (a) provide your name, mail/shipping address, email address, credit card number and phone number when registering with our Website, using our online store, or in connection with a contest entry; (b) provide certain demographic information about you (e.g., age, gender, purchase preference, usage frequency, etc.) when participating in a survey, poll or joining a club; or (c) post a product rating and recommendation on our Website. []Whether or not you provide this personally identifiable information is your choice; however, in many instances this type of information is required to participate in the particular activity, realize a benefit we may offer, or gain access to certain content on our Website. 
  * (2)Non-Personal Information: 
  * Non-personal information is any information that does not personally identify you. Non-personal information can include certain personally identifiable information that has been de-identified; that is, information that has been rendered anonymous. We obtain non-personal information from information that you provide us. and automatically when you access our Website. This information can include, among other things, IP addresses (other than where used to identify individuals), the type of browser you are using (e.g., Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, etc.), the third party website from which your visit originated, the operating system you are using (e.g., Vista, Windows XP, Macintosh OS, etc.), the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., America Online, NetZero, etc.), the search terms you use on our Website, the specific web pages you visit, and the duration of your visits. 

#### B. HOW WE USE & SHARE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED 

(1)Personally Identifiable Information: 

The personally identifiable information you submit to us is generally used to carry out your requests, respond to your inquiries, better serve you, or in other ways naturally associated with the circumstances in which you provided the information. We may also use this information to later contact you for a variety of reasons, such as customer service, providing you promotional information for our products or those of our parent company, subsidiaries or other affiliated companies (“affiliated companies”), or to communicate with you about content or other information you have posted or shared with us via our Website. You may opt-out from receiving future promotional information from us or our affiliated companies, or direct that we not share your information with any affiliated companies, as set forth below. 

In certain instances we may also share your personally identifiable information with our third party vendors performing functions on our behalf (or on behalf of our affiliated companies) e.g., vendors that process credit card orders, deliver our merchandise, administer our promotions, provide us marketing or promotional assistance, analyze our data, assist us with customer service, etc. Our vendors agree to use this information, and we share information with them, only to carry out our requests. 

In addition, we may share your personally identifiable information with participating sponsors to a program or promotion (e.g., a competition or contest) you enter via our Website, and with third parties who assist us in using the content or other information you have posted or shared with us via our Website (e.g., production companies we may use). Further, we may share your personally identifiable information with third parties such as our co-promotional partners and others with whom we have marketing or other relationships.

Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, or as set forth when you submit the information, your personally identifiable information will not be shared or sold to any third parties without your prior approval. 

(2)Non-Personal Information: 

We use non-personal information in a variety of ways, including to help analyze site traffic, understand customer needs and trends, carry out targeted promotional activities, and to improve our services. We may use your non-personal information by itself or aggregate it with information we have obtained from others. We may share your non-personal information with our affiliated companies and third parties to achieve these objectives and others, but remember that aggregate information is anonymous information that does not personally identify you.

#### C. OTHER USES & INFORMATION 

(1)IP Addresses: 

An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Internet. Web servers (computers that “serve up” web pages) automatically identify your computer by its IP address. When visitors request pages from our Website, our servers typically log their IP addresses. We collect IP addresses for purposes of system administration, to report non-personal aggregate information to others, and to track the use of our Website. IP addresses are considered non-personal information (except where used to identify individuals) and may also be shared as provided above. It is not our practice to link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable; that is, the visitor's session will be logged, but the visitor remains anonymous to us. However, we reserve the right to use IP addresses to identify a visitor when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our Website rules or to: (a) fulfill a government request; (b) conform with the requirements of the law or legal process; (c) protect or defend our legal rights or property, our Website, or other users; or (d) in an emergency to protect the health and safety of our Website's users or the general public.

(2)Cookies, etc.: 

We may use cookies and other similar technologies to ensure you get the best from our Website. “Cookies” are small text files from a website that are stored on your computer, mobile phone or other device. These text files make using our Website more convenient by, among other things, recognising you when you return, saving your passwords and preferences and may help us to customise our Website for you based on your preferences. Cookies themselves do not typically contain any personally identifiable information. We may analyze the information derived from these cookies and other similar technological tools we employ (such as clear gifs/web beacons) and match this information with data provided by you or another party. We may provide our analysis and certain non-personal information to third parties (who may in turn use this information to provide advertisements tailored to your interests), but this will not involve disclosing any of your personally identifiable information. 

To optimise your experience on our Website and to help us to improve it, your computer, mobile phone or other device will need to accept cookies. If it doesn't, you may not be able to take advantage of all the features of our Website, including certain personalised features. You can give us your consent by pressing the continue button in the Website when we ask for your consent to use cookies. Here is a list of the main cookies we use and what each cookie is used for:

_First Party Cookies_   
The following cookies are used to improve our Website and do not contain any personal information that would allow us to identify you (such as your name or other contact details). 

**_Cookie Name_** | **_Cookie Purpose_**  
---|---  
SESS* | **Really important cookies**   
This cookie allows our server to recognise you as a returning visitor, in order for us to allow you to log into the website and store user preferences.  
FN_nginx | This cookie is set when you are logged into the website and is used to help our caching servers work out whether to serve you cached pages or not.  
FN_UK_cookie_accept | This cookie is set once you have pressed the "continue" button to tell us you have accepted the use of cookies on our website, to stop us from showing you the message again.  
FN_UK_agecheck | This cookie is set once you have pressed the "confirm" button to tell us you are aged 18 and over to view age-restricted content, to stop us repeating the message on another video.  
**Google Analytics:** _utma, _utmb, _utmc, utmz   
**Ominiture:** s_cc, s_nr, s_ppv, s_sq   
**Chartbeat Analytics:** _chartbeat2   
**Clicktale Analytics:** WRUID  | **Analytics**   
We use analytics software to help analyse use of our website. These cookies enable us to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour, such as new visitor numbers, interactions and paths through our website, response to our marketing campaigns and browser usage, all in an anonymous form. This information is important to help us understand how people use our website, how our website is performing and to make it as easy to use and useful as possible.   
**InSkin Media:** InSkinSessionID, InSkinUserID | **Advertising**   
InSkin Media is our ad serving supplier. They use cookies for the purpose of serving advertisements and ensuring they are relevant to you.   
  
_Third Party Cookies_

**_Cookie Name_** | **_Cookie Purpose_**  
---|---  
**DoubleClick:** NGUserID, id   
**Specific Media:** ug, JSESSIONID  |  **Advertising**   
Our ad serving suppliers, DoubleClick and Specific Media use cookies for the purpose of serving our internet advertisements on other sites. The cookies accompanying the ads allow our suppliers and their advertisers to monitor the effectiveness of the ads and make the ads more relevant to you. Some of our web pages may contain electronic images known as web beacons (sometimes known as clear gifs) that allow us to track user interactions on these pages. They may also report back some information to our ad serving suppliers about the interaction performed.   
**AddThis.com:** dt, loc, psc, uid, uit, uvc   
**Google + 1 button:** NID, PREF  |  **Content Sharing**  
Our suppliers use cookies to give our users a simple way to share content across the social web and tell us how many visitors are sharing content.   
  
Our Website displays video content using Adobe Flash Player. Adobe uses Flash cookies (also known as Local Shared Objects) to help improve your user experience. Flash cookies are stored on your computer, mobile phone or other device in much the same way as usual cookies, but your browser manages them differently. If you wish to disable or delete a Flash cookie, see Adobe Flashplayer Security Settings. Please bear in mind though, that if you disable Flash cookies for the Website you'll be unable to access certain types of content on the Website, such as videos.

We sometimes carry embedded "Share" and "Like" buttons to enable our users to easily share articles through social networks such as Facebook and Twitter. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged into their service. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

We also sometimes embed content from websites such as YouTube. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from these websites you may be presented with cookies from these websites. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

Please note that advertisers that serve advertisements on our Website may also use their own cookies and other similar technological tools which are subject to the advertiser's privacy policies, not this Privacy Policy. We have no control over cookies placed on our Website by these third parties.

**It is a condition of using our Website that you accept these cookies, so please be aware that if you restrict or prevent them, we cannot guarantee how our Website will work for you. If you continue to use and browse our Website, you are consenting to cookies being used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.**

If you are concerned about the storage and use of cookies, you may be able to direct your internet browser to notify you and seek approval whenever a cookie is being sent to your computer, mobile phone or other device. You may also delete a cookie manually from your computer, mobile phone or other device through your internet browser or other programs. Please note, however, that some parts of our Website will not function properly or be available to you if you refuse to accept a cookie or choose to disable the acceptance of cookies. 

For more information on how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, please go to [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

The internet advertising industry has also produced a guide to online privacy and behavioural advertising, please see [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/). 

We may change and update our list of cookies from time to time. If you use our cookies after we have published these changes, you will be agreeing to be bound by those changes. If you do not consent to the use of the cookies at any time, please see above on how to disable cookies.

(3)Email Communications: 

If you send us an email with questions or comments, we may use your personally identifiable information to respond to your questions or comments, and we may save your questions or comments for future reference. For security reasons, we do not recommend that you send non-public personal information, such as passwords, social security numbers, or bank account information, to us by email. However, aside from our reply to such an email, it is not our standard practice to send you email unless you request a particular service or sign up for a feature that involves email communications, it relates to purchases you have made with us (e.g., product updates, customer support, etc.), we are sending you information about our other products and services, or you consented to being contacted by email for a particular purpose. In certain instances, we may provide you with the option to set your preferences for receiving email communications from us; that is, agree to some communications but not others. You may “opt out” of receiving future commercial email communications from us by clicking the “unsubscribe” link included at the bottom of most emails we send, or as provided below; provided, however, we reserve the right to send you transactional emails such as customer service communications. 

(4)Transfer of Assets"

As we continue to develop our business, we may sell or purchase assets. If another entity acquires us or all (or substantially all) of our assets, the personally identifiable information and non-personal information we have about you will be transferred to and used by this acquiring entity, though we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your preferences are followed. Also, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, all such information may be considered an asset of ours and as such may be sold or transferred to third parties. 

(5)Other: 

Notwithstanding anything herein to the contrary, we reserve the right to disclose any personally identifiable or non-personal information about you if we are required to do so by law, with respect to notices and counternotices pursuant to our DMCA notice and takedown policy and procedures and/or if we believe that such action is necessary to: (a) fulfill a government request; (b) conform with the requirements of the law or legal process; (c) protect or defend our legal rights or property, our Website, or other users; or (d) in an emergency to protect the health and safety of our Website's users or the general public.

#### D. WHERE WE STORE YOUR INFORMATION

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to and stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"), including the USA. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for the organization that hosts the Website. By submitting your information you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Unfortunately transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

#### E. PUBLIC FORUMS 

We may offer chat rooms, message boards, bulletin boards, or similar public forums where you and other users of our Website can communicate. The protections described in this Privacy Policy do not apply when you provide information (including personal information) in connection with your use of these public forums. We may use personally identifiable and non-personal information about you to identify you with a posting in a public forum. Any information you share in a public forum is public information and may be seen or collected by anyone, including third parties that do not adhere to our Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for events arising from the distribution of any information you choose to publicly post or share through our Website. 

#### F. CHILDREN 

The features, programs, promotions and other aspects of our Website requiring the submission of personally identifiable information are not intended for children. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 and believe he or she has disclosed personally identifiable information to us please contact us at privacy@foodnetwork.co.uk. A parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 may review and request deletion of such child's personally identifiable information as well as prohibit the use thereof.

#### G.  KEEPING YOUR INFORMATION SECURE 

We have implemented security measures we consider reasonable and appropriate to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Please be advised, however, that while we strive to protect your personally identifiable information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and are not responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your personally identifiable information. In the unfortunate event that your “personally identifiable information” (as the term or similar terms are defined by any applicable law requiring notice upon a security breach) is compromised, we may notify you by e-mail (at our sole and absolute discretion) to the last e-mail address you have provided us in the most expedient time reasonable under the circumstances; provided, however, delays in notification may occur while we take necessary measures to determine the scope of the breach and restore reasonable integrity to the system as well as for the legitimate needs of law enforcement if notification would impede a criminal investigation. From time to time we evaluate new technology for protecting information, and when appropriate, we upgrade our information security systems.

#### H. OTHER SITES / LINKS

Our Website may link to or contain links to other third party websites that we do not control or maintain, such as in connection with purchasing products referenced on our Website and banner advertisements. We are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by any third party website. We encourage you to note when you leave our Website and to read the privacy statements of all third party websites before submitting any personally identifiable information. 

#### I. CONTACT & OPT-OUT INFORMATION 

You may contact us as at privacy@foodnetwork.co.uk if: (a) you have questions or comments about our Privacy Policy; (b) wish to make corrections to any personally identifiable information you have provided; (c) want to opt-out from receiving future commercial correspondence, including emails, from us or our affiliated companies; or (d) wish to withdraw your consent to sharing your personally identifiable information with others.

The Data Protection Act 1998 gives you the right to access information held about you and the right to apply for rectification, blocking, erasure and destruction of inaccurate information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. Please send your access request to privacy@foodnetwork.co.uk.

We will respond to your request and, if applicable and appropriate, make the requested change in our active databases as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that we may not be able to fulfill certain requests while allowing you access to certain benefits and features of our Website. 

#### J. SOLE STATEMENT

This Privacy Policy as posted on this Site is the sole statement of our privacy policy with respect to this Site, and no summary, modification, restatement or other version thereof, or other privacy statement or policy, in any form, is valid unless we post a new or revised policy to the Site.

Effective: November 12, 2008 © 2008 Scripps Networks International (UK) Limited. All Rights Reserved.
